Guilherme Branco Stracini



guilherme@guilhermebranco.com.br



+55 11 97265-9788



linkedin.com/in/guilhermestracini



https://guilherme.stracini.com

Summary

Currently working in Farfetch which is a leading global platform in the luxury fashion online market, under Agile culture using C# (.NET Core), Apache Cassandra, Apache Kafka, Elastic Search, Jenkins and other tools to improve quality of deliverables.

Also working part-time remotely for The Bridge Social, for Grace Kennedy client, the biggest Financial and Food group in Jamaica and Caribbean area. Developing digital wallet and remittance projects.

Previously worked on a bank, for an year and a half. During this period, participated on two teams (PIX and B2B) developing the PIX (Brazilian Instant Payments system), also developing APIs and Open Banking integrations, direct contact with clients B2B, regulatory agencies, other banks and technical teams to provide the best solution for both sides! Using .NET Core, SQL Server, RabbitMQ supported by DDD architecture, SOLID, DRY & KISS principles.

I am excited to contribute my strengths and proficiency in innovation toward your team efforts. As an extroverted and personable communicator with a proven track record in technical writing, my focus on building strong professional relationships has been a valuable asset throughout my career.

Software engineer, well experienced with C#, working with financial services, e-commerce, integrations, web and desktop solutions.

Check out some projects I worked on:

- Integration with Western Union for remittance across countries.
- Digital wallet (payments, transfers, remittance, balance, statement, mobile top-up, credit card).
- PIX Brazilian Instantly Payments System (SPI/PIX BACEN).
- Microservices using gRPC for communication intra-process.
- Distributed systems using RabbitMQ and Apache Kafka.
- Gateway integrations with MaxiPago, Adyen and PayPal.
- OnBoarding and Internet Banking projects for B2B customers.
- Vitrine do Artesanato (integration) e-commerce.
- VTEX e-commerce PaaS (integration).
- Sankhya ERP (management, analysis, integration).
- Vitrine do Artesanato Digital digital video platform (development).
- Vitrine do Artesanato na TV digital video content portal (development).
- Canal do Artesanato subscription learning platform (development).
- Zendesk (integration).
- SAP (integration).
- Database (management).
- Agile Methodologies.
- Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC).
- General web development.
- Some integrations libraries in C#, PHP, Rust and JS, available at https://github.com/guibranco

Experience

F Senior Software Engineer

FARFETCH

Dec 2020 - Present (5 months +)

Being part of Search & Scouts team:

- Development of improvements in the search services of the platform
- Development solutions using Kafka, Cassandra, C# (.NET Core), Elastic Search.
- Agile culture & cerimonies using Scrum and Kanban over Jira

Senior Software Engineer

The Bridge Social

Feb 2021 - Present (3 months +)

Part-time job, working remotely for Grace Kennedy (Jamaica & Caribbean area) client, building:

- Remittance integration with Western Union
- Digital wallet system
- Building API and Services with C# (.NET Core 3.1 and .NET 5), using CosmosDB, Microsoft Azure Service Bus, Entity Framework Core, Dapper, Application Insights
- Agile culture & cerimonies using Scrum and Kanban over Azure DevOps

https://www.gracekennedy.com/

ы Senior Software Engineer

BS2 Hub

Jul 2019 - Jan 2021 (1 year 7 months)

- Implementation of PIX (Brazilian Instantly Payments BACEN)
- Development of API banking product (https://devs.bs2.com) BaaS
- Development of open banking project
- Development of APIs using .NET Core, Dapper, Entity Framework, RabbitMQ and DDD
- Deploy and development using Docker containers
- Supporting clients in integration process
- Agile culture & cerimonies using Scrum and Kanban over Team Foundation Service (TFS) and Azure DevOps



🧰 Software Developer

C&A Brasil

Dec 2018 - Jun 2019 (7 months)

- Development of integrations solutions using Zendesk, SAP, Oracle and other internal systems
- Automation of payment/refund process using Adyen gateway
- Automation of process using .NET Core
- Implement ElasticSearch and Kibana for log & metrics in e-commerce team
- Develop new features and APIs using NodeJS (Express & HAPI)
- Develop of an unified library in .NET Core to be used internally by all teams, with commons & utils needs

- Agile culture & cerimonies using Scrum and Kanban over Jira

Project Development Coordinator

Editora Inovacao Ltda [Inovacao Media Brazil Group]

Jan 2016 - Nov 2018 (2 years 11 months)

- Head of development of IT department. Managing dev's team, agencies and associates.
- Implement SOLID principles.
- Implement Apache Kafka for distributed systems process
- Implement ElasticSearch and Kibana for log & metrics purproses
- Development of an internal search engine using data from ElasticSearch (clients, orders and orders items)
- Deploy, evangelize and speech of continuous integration and continuous delivery (CI/CD)
- Agile culture & cerimonies using Scrum and Kanban over Trello and RunRun.It

Software Development Analyst

Editora Inovacao Ltda [Inovacao Media Brazil Group]

Nov 2013 - Dec 2015 (2 years 2 months)

- Website development using ASP.NET C # technology and MVC standard.
- API 2 (C #) web applications for user data access (via client web application) and restricted access data management of other internal projects.
- Application development for product and order integration with the Smart Checkout / VTEX platform.
- Payment gateway integration MaxiPago for subscription management
- Management of triggers and procedures in SQL Server 2008 database.
- Disaster Management / Automated Backup Plans on SQL Server and Windows Server.
- Automated backup for Amazon Web Service S3.

IT Analyst

Editora Inovacao Ltda [Inovacao Media Brazil Group]

Nov 2012 - Oct 2013 (1 year)

- Development of video portal using C # language and MVC standard.
- Development of service integration tool (via Web Service and API) in C #.
- Monitoring and management of SQL Server database.
- Requirements gathering.
- Planning, modeling, implementation and process documentation ERP (Sankhya).

Intern - IT

Editora Inovacao Ltda [Inovacao Media Brazil Group]

Nov 2011 - Oct 2012 (1 year)

- Development of email marketing.
- Training, maintenance and installation of micro computers.
- Configuration and installation of software.
- Development of internal systems in VB.NET
- Development of complementary tools for existing projects in classic ASP and PHP.

Education

FATEC - São Caetano do Sul - Antônio Russo

Analysis and system development, College - technologist 2011 - 2013

Senac Brasil

Computer technician, Informatics 2008 - 2010 Computer technician course - 1000 hours, presencial classes.

ETEC Prof. Camargo Aranha

High School Diploma, High School/Secondary Diplomas and Certificates 2007 - 2009

Skills

C# • Design Patterns • Software Documentation • Unit Testing • Continuous Integration • Continuous Delivery • Representational State Transfer (REST) • Microservices • Microsoft Azure • Messaging